

CURRICULUM VITAE

Danelle Devi-Hollenbeck, M.S, LMHC, HCPC, MBPsS

Counselling Psychologist. EMDR Trained and listed on EMDR UK and Ireland

Health City, Davenport House, 16 Pepper Street, Canary Wharf, London E14 9RP. Tel: 0333 800 3006, 0333 789 0012. Email: info@healthcity.org.uk Website: http://www.healthcity.org.uk/

PROFILE

A female and a senior therapist in Health City. Consultant Counselling Psychologist specialising in trauma and couples issues. She has worked as a consultant for various NHS trusts and acute psych wards. Danelle is EMDR Trained and has certification in the USA and UK. Danelle uses various CBT modalities, specifically TF CBT. however, she specialises in EMDR to work through trauma using EMDR, EMD, Rtep and Gtep. She also uses the Gottman Institute training for couples therapy. Aside from trauma and couples, Ms. Hollenbeck treats anxiety, depression, mood disorders, and family problems.

Ms. Hollenbeck has plus 15 years working in the mental health and addiction field in the UK and USA with an emphasis on opioid addiction and treatment where she has completed research in this area.

EDUCATION

- 13/5/2015 to 31/5/2016: Kaplan University: M.S. Psychology
- 03/7/2014: University of West London, UK B.S. Honors Addiction Counselling Studies
- 04/06/2019 to 01/06/2021: HCPC Registration PYL37004
- FDAP Registration
- Licensed in the United States as a Mental Health Counselor #MH16140, which consisted of a post graduate training that is the UK equivalent of Doctoral level training.

TRAINING

- EMDR Training and Listed on EMDRIA.org and EMDR UK & Ireland
- 19-21/1 and 2-4/3/2017: EMDR R-Tep and G-Tep trained through Connect EMDR
- Crisis Intervention & Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Training (Certified)
- 26/5/2017: CBT Basic, Anxiety, and Depression from The Beck Institute
- 12/7/2017: CBT for Depression from The Beck Institute

- 10/12/2013: Motivational Interviewing Certified CNWL NHS Trust).
- Trauma Focused Cognitive Behavioural Therapy (TF-CBT).
- Substance Abuse. Suicide Prevention.
- Group Therapy
- Mindfulness, Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT).
- Rational Emotive Behavioural Therapy (REBT).
- Gestalt Therapy. Person-Centered, Gottman Couples Counselling, Vicarious Trauma.
- Management and Supervision training

STRENGTHS: Reliable, works well within a multidisciplinary team and independently, flexible, strong communication and organizational skills, works well in a fast- paced environment with frequent interruptions. Works equally well with all genders. Decision maker with proven ability to handle situations with tact and diplomacy. Uses MI to help develop positive rapport and solutions when working with service users and leading a team.

WORK HISTORY

2019- Present- Counselling Psychologist, Health City, London:

- Specialist assessments and treatment of trauma, mood disorders, depression, eating disorders, anxiety and most psychological problems.
- Provides cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT), EMDR trauma therapy, trauma focused cognitive behavioural therapy (TFCBT), motivational interviewing, family systems therapy, couple therapy, Solution-Focused Brief Therapy (SFBT) and other evidenced based therapies.

<u>2019-Present- Counselling Psychologist Band 7b Locum CAMHS Cambridgeshire, UK.</u>

- Provides multi-disciplinary and specialist psychological assessment and treatment for children and adolescents with emotional, behavioural and mental health problems, their carers/parents and families.
- Undertakes parenting support.
- Contributes to audit and research.
- > Advocating for people using the services.
- Providing supervision to non-qualified staff.
- Working closely with external partners including GP's, schools etc.

2016- Present- Therapist of Empathy Counselling

- Conducts specialist assessments and treatment and risk assessments of trauma, mood disorders, depression, eating disorders, anxiety, etc.
- > Provides sessions in compliance with court ordered drug treatment.
- Conducts therapeutic supervised visits as court ordered
- Provides cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT), EMDR trauma therapy, trauma focused cognitive behavioural therapy (TFCBT),

Gottman and Family, Solution-Focused Brief Therapy (SFBT) and Couple therapy and other evidenced based therapies.

2018-2019 Clinical Coordinator Part-Time for Juvenile Welfare Program

- Provided mental health and/or substance abuse assessments and counselling services to youth assessed or referred for mental health and/or substance abuse services.
- Assessed youth identified with suicide risk factors within 24 hours, or immediately if the youth is in imminent danger of self-harm.
- Utilized Motivational Interviewing (MI), Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) and provided an awareness and understanding of the impact of trauma on behavior.
- Provide psycho-education as well as group treatment.

2016 <u>-2019- Chrysalis Health- Lead Outpatient Therapist &</u> Licensed Assessor

- Provide highly specialist psychological assessments, interpretation from psychological tests, semi-structured interviews, individual and group therapy. Considered risks and social needs of the client group, relevant to their diagnosis.
- Responsible for supervising a minimum of three (3) therapists per year.
- Provide group work to teens and adults
- > Provided community referrals for GUM clinic and social welfare.
- Ability to work effectively with culturally diverse individuals experiencing an exacerbation of either psychiatric, substance use and/or medical symptoms.
- Ability to work with culturally diverse groups and individuals while experiencing stressful situations.

2014-2015 Acting Team Leader, United Kingdom Locum Work

Managed and led multi-professional team in the delivery of evidence-based interventions.

2009-2014 Substance Misuse/Dual Diagnosis Practitioner, United Kingdom, Locum Work

- Provided opiate substitute prescribing using Advantage 2000
- Conducted in-depth biopsychosocial assessments
- ➤ 1:1 sessions of M.I., CBT, ITEP mapping, SFT, Mindfulness, & relapse prevention

Research Experience

Kaplan University PSI CHI Research Committee Member"What is the number of heroin-related deaths in the U.S in 2014 in comparison with those from 2005-2010 and 2010-2013?"

"How effective is CBT and DBT in treating co-morbidity"-Published 2012

PUBLICATIONS-PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP-VOLUNTEER WORK

- ➤ EMDRA UK and Ireland Full Member for EMDR (H0514)
- ➤ NIH Research Certificate # 1796051
- ➤ American Psychological Society #9998-5877
- ➤ British Psychological Society #376628
- > PSI CHI International Honor Society Secretary
- "Mindfulness Based Cognitive Therapy for PTSD", PSI CHI Newsletter, winter, 2015.
- > Writing on various topics in on mental health, relationship issues, anxiety and mood disorders for various blogs
- ➤ Volunteer for the French Bulldog Welfare Trust